Joshua Wyllie

software engineer

jwyllie.co.nz joshuawyllie@live.com (+64) 022 137 9514 Hi, I'm a computer science graduate with a passion for innovation. In my free time I like going to the gym, running, skiing (NZSIA qualified ski instructor) as well as language learning (>2 year Duolingo streak). I'm personally interested in machine learning and functional/alternative programming languages, and exploring these though side projects (mostly private repo's)



Experience

Solnet — Junior Software Engineer

SEPTEMBER 2019 - PRESENT, WELLINGTON NZ

Lead the development and support of several back-end systems using Node.js on AWS serverless technologies (Lambda, DynamoDB, etc.) to provide a critical system for the Ministry of Health. Supported applications for a vaiety of clients (PHP, TS, React, Angular).

NoNoRank — Intern Developer

MARCH 2019 - JUNE 2019, UPPSALA SE

Worked on various tasks at the search engine startup. This included a machine learning classification task, implementing the cache, as well as broader design/planning.

Education

Uppsala University — Exchange Program

FEBRUARY 2016 - JUNE 2019, UPPSALA SE

Completed my studies while on exchange in Sweden. Earned return flight scolarship.

University of Canturbury — BSc Computer Science

FEBRUARY 2016 - JUNE 2019, CHRISTCHURCH NZ

Additional papers in Physics, Economics, and Statistics. Much project work.

Certifications

AWS Certified Developer Accossiate

AUGUST 2020 - AUGUST 2023

Projects

GitHub

https://github.com/j-wyllie - see for more projects

ODMS — Java Application

Organ Donation Management System developed in a team of 9 over a year. Followed strictly the Agile Scrum

KeepMoving — Android Game

Developed using Java with the LibGDX framework. Can be found on the playstore here: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.joshuawyllie.game

Technologies

TypeScript, JavaScript, Node.js Angular, React, PHP, SilverStripe, Java, Python, C, Linux, BASH, Git, OpenGL, LibGDX, SQL, HTML, CSS